Guide to the David Wojnarowicz Papers ca. 1954-1992 MSS 092
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XIII: Objects and Artifacts
  - Subseries A: General Objects and Artifacts
    - Title: Figurine--Elephant, undated (Folder 092.2.0199)
      Description: Elephant walking
      Materials: wood
      Dimensions: x inches
    - Title: Cross, undated (Folder 092.2.0200)
      Description: Wooden cross with remnants of veneer
      Materials: wood, Formica veneer (marble finish)
      Dimensions: 16 x 9 x 1 inches
    - Title: Figurine, undated (Folder 092.2.0201)
      Description: Virgin of Guadalupe, hands in prayer, full body halo, held up by cherub; figure on a pedestal
      Dimensions: 5.5 x 2.25 x 2.15 inches
    - Title: Figurine, undated (Folder 092.2.0202)
      Description: Figure of female saint, holding torch, bible, and ? incense burner, standing on a snake
      Dimensions: 4.25 x 1.35 x 1.35 inches
    - Title: Picture, undated (Folder 092.2.0203)
      Description: Framed postcard of Hindu gods Krishna and Hanuman (monkey general) embracing each other. Blue and gold border; in plastic frame
      Materials: paper, plastic
      Dimensions: 6 x 4 x 1.5 inches
    - Title: Picture Religious Artifacts, undated (Folder 092.2.0204)
      Description: Print of female saint holding cross, wearing a black habit, halo around head; image affixed to wooden board for hanging--in original plastic wrap
      Materials: paper, wood, plastic
      Dimensions: 12 x 10 x 0.25 inches
    - Title: Devotional Necklace, undated (Folder 092.2.0205)
      Description: Pennant on string--printed image of Virgin Mary attached to green felt, encased in plastic. Back inscription re: Immaculate Heart of Mary
      Materials: plastic, cloth, felt, string
      Dimensions: 2 x 1.75 x 0.15 inches
    - Title: Devotional Necklace--In package, undated (Folder 092.2.0206)
      Description: Same as item 092.0206 in original, unopened package--pendant of Virgin Mary, on cloth, encased in plastic, on green string.
      Materials: plastic, cloth, string, glue
      Dimensions: 3.9 x 2.5 x 0.15 inches
    - Title: Box, undated (Folder 092.2.0207)
      Description: Metal box featuring open scroll--work design of grape vines around two lions facing each other, wooden interior
      Materials: metal, wood
      Dimensions: 1.75 x 5.5 x 3.35 inches
    - Title: Box, undated (Folder 092.2.0208)
      Description: Tin Box, cover reads "J.G. Dill's Best Cat plug, Richmond, VA, picture of woman; yellow, brown & green
      Maker: J.G. Dill
      Where Made: Richmond, VA
      Materials: tin, paint
      Dimensions: 1.5 x 4.35 x 3.25 inches
    - Title: Box, undated (Folder 092.2.0209)
      Description: Carved and stained wooden box; alternating geometric design of floral & circular motifs, stained in green, yellow
      Maker: bottom label in Eastern European language
      Materials: wood, pigment
      Dimensions: 2 x 7.75 x 5 inches
    - Title: Box, undated (Folder 092.2.0210)
      Description: Box styled to look like a wicker trunk, with three buckled straps on top, crown on center strap, keyhole front of box
      Materials: wood, metal, cloth and paper in interior
    - Title: Box with contents, undated (Folder 092.2.0211)
      Description: Box covered in geometric print cloth, cloth-lined, with surgical cotton inside.
      Materials: cloth, cardboard
      Dimensions: 1.75 x 3.75 x 3 inches
    - Title: Box of trading cards, undated (Folder 092.2.0212)
      Description: Leather embossed lock--floral motif border, heart, spade, and diamond playing cards on center top; contents--mixed set of trading cards-- 1 set cowboy and Indian cards by Hassan cigarettes; set 2--Arctic themed cards by Hassan cigarettes; set 3--athletes--by Mecca cigarettes, miniature pencil 46 cards total
      Materials: leather, cardboard, ribbon
      Dimensions: 1.35 x 6 x 4 inches
    - Title: Box of Incense, undated (Folder 092.2.0213)
      Description: Juniper Incense in small brick shapes
      Maker: Incense de Santa Fe--printed on back of box
      Where Made: Santa Fe, New Mexico--printed on back of box
      Materials: cardboard, plastic, incense
      Dimensions: 2 x 3 x 3 inches
    - Title: Box, undated (Folder 092.2.0214)
      Description: Pill box, smooth finish, metal
      Materials: metal--?brass
      Dimensions: 0.85 x 2.65 x 1.85 inches
    - Title: Pill Box, undated (Folder 092.2.0215)
      Description: Pill Box with cover design of holly berries & leaves and scroll reading "Happy New Year"; contents: 2 grains of rice and seeds, possibly poppy or mustard
      Materials: tin, rice, seeds
      Dimensions: 0.5 x 1.5 x 1.25 inches
    - Title: Playing Cards, 1953 (Folder 092.2.0216)
      Description: Boxed deck of "Round Up" card game, front & back cover depicts cowboy on horse, pistols, rifle, 45 cards
      Maker: Whitman Publishing Company, printed on "Rules" card
      Materials: cardboard
      Dimensions: 3.65 x 1.85 x 0.75 inches
    - Title: Playing Cards, undated (Folder 09.2.2021)
      Description: Boxed deck of game cards featuring pictures on one side, description in Spanish on back; box reads "Loteria, la serie" 54 cards
      Where Made: Leo, S.A. printed on card and box (South America?)
      Dimensions: 3.75 x 2.5 x 0.75 inches
    - Title: Pig, undated (Folder 092.2.0218)
      Description: Papier-Mache pig made of color comic strips (newspaper) in Philipino
      Maker: none, possibly David Wojnarowicz
      Materials: newspaper, paste
      Dimensions: 8.5 x 5 x 13.5 inches
    - Title: Head, undated (Folder 092.2.0219)
      Description: Papier--Mache head with sharp teeth and big ears, painted, hand made, possibly unfinished
      Materials: newspaper, paste, paint, masking tape
      Dimensions: 8.75 x 8.5 x 8.25 inches
    - Title: Bird, undated (Folder 092.2.0220)
      Description: Carved and stained wooden box
      Materials: newspaper, paste, paint
      Dimensions: 7.75 x 12 x 15.25 inches
    - Title: Sperm, undated (Folder 092.2.0221)
      Description: Sculpture of sperm, light blue, soft form
      Maker: none, but possibly David Wojnarowicz
      Materials: newspaper, masking tape, paint
      Dimensions: 9.5 x 13 x 17 inches
    - Title: Penis, undated (Folder 092.2.0222)
      Description: Stylized sculpture of phallus with two spherical balls
      Materials: cast plaster
      Dimensions: 10.5 x 7.25 x 7 inches
    - Title: Mexican folk sculpture, undated (Folder 092.2.0223)
      Description: Stylized folk sculpture, totem-like combination of claws, serpent, skull, multiple faces
      Materials: ceramic, patina or paint wash
      Dimensions: 13 x 8.25 x 7 inches
    - Title: Doll/Marionette, undated (Folder 092.2.0224)
      Description: Hand-made doll made from newspaper with smiling face and triangular teeth, string attached to necknote: not freestanding
      Materials: newspaper, masking tape, paint, string
      Dimensions: 16 x 4 x 2.5 inches
    - Title: Head, undated (Folder 092.2.0225)
      Description: Head of male, green
      Materials: fired clay?
      Dimensions: 4.5 x 2.75 x 4 inches
    - Title: Salt/Pepper Shaker, undated (Folder 092.2.0226)
      Description: Salt or pepper shaker in form of lady's head with two pairs of eyes (part of set-see item 092.0227)
      Dimensions: 3.25 x 2.25 x 2 inches
    - Title: Salt/Pepper Shaker, undated (Folder 092.2.0227)
      Description: Salt or pepper shaker in form of Man's head with two pairs of eyes (part of set, see item 092.0226)
      Dimensions: 3.25 x 2.25 x 1.5 inches
    - Title: Gorilla head, undated (Folder 092.2.0228)
      Description: Head of gorilla with open mouth baring teeth
      Maker: bottom stamped "RTC: Chicago made in Hong Kong"
      Dimensions: 3.5 x 2 x 2.25 inches
    - Title: Witch face, undated (Folder 092.2.0229)
      Description: Traditional "witch" face with warts on hose and chin, pointed hat; yellow, black, red.
      Maker: Inside stamped "Ben Cooper, Inc.; Made in Hong Kong"
      Dimensions: 2.75 x 2.15 x 1.25 inches
    - Title: Head, undated (Folder 092.2.0230)
      Description: Head of male with flower pot style hat, probably once attached to a body; green, orange, red
      Dimensions: 2.25 x 2 x 1.75 inches
    - Title: Witch Head, undated (Folder 092.2.0231)
      Description: Head with long nose, warts, open mouth with two fang teeth and orange-blonde hair; white, red, black
      Where Made: bottom left stamped "Made in Hong Kong"
      Materials: plastic, hair, glue, elastic string
      Dimensions: 4 x 3 x 5.5 inches
    - Title: Hand Puppet--Bird, undated (Folder 092.2.0232)
      Description: Bird face with striped cloth "sock" attached; yellow, red, black, white, green
      Dimensions: 3.5 x 3 x 12 inches
    - Title: Jar with Devil's Face, undated (Folder 092.2.0233)
      Description: Head of "devil" with opening on top to function as jar, orange head with small horns, black and white face with moustache and goatee
      Maker: bottom printed "Victoria, Carlsbad, Austria.
      Where Made: porcelain or ceramic
      Materials: 3.5
      Dimensions: 3.25 x 4.5 inches
    - Title: Mask, undated (Folder 092.2.0235)
      Description: Small mask or face with all-over pattern of gouges, mouth asymmetrical, hand-carved, two holes on side for hanging
      Maker: inside right, in pencil, "AW"
      Dimensions: 3.75 x 2.5 x 1.5 inches
    - Title: Head, undated (Folder 092.2.0236)
      Description: Head with ears on top, hollow in back and on bottom
      Materials: carved wood
      Dimensions: 3.5 x 2 x 2 inches
    - Title: Head, undated (Folder 092.2.0237)
      Description: Male head with exposed brain, dark green and black
      Dimensions: 5.75 x 4.5 x 5.75 inches
    - Title: Skull, undated (Folder 092.2.0238)
      Description: Red skull with smile; back stamped with candy ingredients--toy with candy purchase
      Where Made: back stamped "Made in Hong Kong"
      Dimensions: 3.25 x 2.25 x 2.5 inches
    - Title: Skull, undated (Folder 092.2.0239)
      Description: White skull with green and pink conical hat, possibly Mexican
      Materials: clay, paint
      Dimensions: 1 x 0.3 x 0.3 inches
    - Title: Brains, undated (Folder 092.2.0240)
      Description: Clear, hallow brain
      Dimensions: 2.25 x 4.25 x 5.15 inches
    - Title: Brain, undated (Folder 092.2.0241)
      Description: Soft, hollow brain; green and black
      Dimensions: 3.35 x 4.5 x 6 inches
    - Title: Sculpture, undated (Folder 092.2.0242)
      Description: Abstract brain-like sculpture, hollow, gray
      Dimensions: 3.25 x 5 x 4.75 inches
    - Title: Skull in Box, 1977, printed right side (Folder 092.2.0243)
      Description: Glow-in-the-dark life-sized skull in unopened original packaging, unassembled
      Maker: Revell, printed upper left front corner
      Where Made: Made in Mexican, printed right side
      Materials: plastic, cardboard
      Dimensions: 10 x 7.75 x 3.5 inches
    - Title: Ball, undated (Folder 092.2.0244)
      Description: Ball depicting intertwining snake body and face, green
      Dimensions: 3 x
    - Title: Ashtray, undated (Folder 092.2.0245)
      Description: Ashtray in shape of lungs, right lung has "cancer" patch of red, black & white, left lung reads "Lung Cancer Ashtray"; severely broken
      Maker: bottom reads, "you'd better quit" XXO Becky" and "#3"
      Dimensions: 9.25 x 8.5 x 1 inches
    - Title: Plate, 1984 (Folder 092.2.0246)
      Description: Hand-made plate, broken in four pieces, depicts toxic dump site and reads "Dioxin Kills, They Dump it and it always spills." Multi-colored
      Maker: bottom inscribed "R, Howland, 1984, #15"
      Dimensions: 10 x
    - Title: Sculpture, 1983 (Folder 092.2.0247)
      Description: Cast sculpture of tongue searching an ear--"Sound Search", green and red
      Maker: Back inscribed "for David, Sound Search, Kiki Smith, 1983, AP."
      Dimensions: 6.5 x 6.5 x 3.25 inches
    - Title: Plate, 10.25.84 (Folder 092.2.0248)
      Description: Hand-made plate depicting mines, reads "coal diamonds ashes dust; pick the bones and then go bust" multi-color
      Maker: inscribed "R. Howland, 10.25.84, "12"
      Dimensions: 9.75 x
    - Title: Ashtray, undated (Folder 092.2.0249)
      Description: Ashtray depicting the White House with fountains in front. Top reads "White House, Washington, DC" price tag of $1.59 on back
      Dimensions: 0.5 x 5.75 x 4.25 inches
    - Title: Sno-globe, undated (Folder 092.2.0250)
      Description: Sno-globe of witch at her cauldron, black snow, and "Happy Halloween" printed on front of base; water partially evaporated
      Maker: bottom stamped "C. amscan Inc.
      Materials: plastic, paint, water
      Dimensions: 3.65 x 2.25
    - Title: Sno-globe, undated (Folder 092.2.0251)
      Description: Sno-globe with Disney character "Donald Duck" dressed as Santa Claus, riding a sled, carrying presents: water partially evaporated.
      Maker: non
      Where Made: "Made in Hong Kong" stamped on bottom
      Dimensions: 3.75 x 2.85
    - Title: Stack of compact disks, undated (Folder 092.2.0252)
      Description: Compact disks glued together and shellacked; broken in half
      Materials: compact disks, glue, shellac
      Dimensions: 2 x 4.75
    - Title: Metal Printing block (Burning Man), undated (Folder 092.2.0253)
      Description: Wood block with metal printing plate attached, bottom left surface of wood cut away; image is out of "Burning Man"
      Maker: David Wojnarowicz (no mark)
      Materials: wood, metal, glue, ink
      Dimensions: 8.15 x 7.5 x 0.95 inches
    - Title: Metal printing block (Crashing House), undated (Folder 092.2.0254)
      Description: Wood block with metal printing plate attached. Image is of a house crashing down on ground
      Dimensions: 6.15 x 8.5 x 0.85 inches
    - Title: Metal printing block, undated (Folder 092.2.0255)
      Description: Wood block with metal printing plate attached; image of male head
      Dimensions: 6.85 x 6 x 85 inches
    - Title: Etching Plate, 1988-1989 (Folder 092.2.0256)
      Description: Etching plate for work titled "Brain-Time" (1988-89) depicting a brain with clock face without hands. Shown on p.19 in "Tongues of Flame"
      Maker: David Wojnarowicz
      Dimensions: 6 x 7.85 x 0.15 inches
    - Title: Etching Plate, undated (Folder 092.2.0257)
      Description: Unused etching plate
      Materials: metal, tar or ink
      Dimensions: 6 x 7.65 x 0.15 inches
    - Title: Wall decoration (cat face), undated (Folder 092.2.0258)
      Description: Wall decoration in shape of cat head; marbles attached for eyes
      Materials: metal, glass marbles, tape, plastic, string, pushpin
      Dimensions: 5.5 x 5.75 inches
    - Title: Stamp, undated (Folder 092.2.0259)
      Description: Rubber stamp reads "DAVID WOJNAROWICZ" in capital letters
      Materials: wood, rubber
      Dimensions: 0.5 x 1.85 x 2.5 inches
    - Title: Stamp Kit, undated (Folder 092.2.0260)
      Description: Kit consists of upper and lower case letters, numbers, and various symbols; upper and lower case letters, numbers, and various symbols; ruler, metal guide; in green box; set appears to be complete
      Maker: label on side of box cover reads "Columbia, sign and chart printers, 02"
      Materials: wood, rubber, ink
    - Title: Camera, undated (Folder 092.2.0261)
      Description: Konica autoreflex A 1000 manual camera in leather case
      Maker: Konica--on front of camera and lens cap
      Where Made: Japan--stamped on back right of leather case
      Materials: metal, plastic, glass, leather
      Dimensions: 4.5 x 6 x 4 inches
    - Title: Camera, undated (Folder 092.2.0262)
      Description: Konica manual camera in leather case, lens cap missing
      Maker: Konica--on front of camera and case
      Where Made: Japan "Made in Japan" stamped on back right of case
      Materials: Metal, plastic, glass, leather
      Dimensions: 4.25 x 6.5 x 3.25 inches
    - Title: Keychain, undated (Folder 092.2.0263)
      Description: Keychain with miniature toy camera attached, black and gold
      Materials: plastic, metal
      Dimensions: 1.75 x 2.25 x 1.65 inches
    - Title: Box of splicing tape (super 8 sound), undated (Folder 092.2.0264)
      Description: Box containing six individual packets of splicing tape for super 8 film, each packet contains 50 pieces, instructions in German.
      Maker: Wurker--printed on box and packets
      Where Made: "Made in Germany" printed on box and packets
      Materials: splicing tape, cardboard
      Dimensions: 7.25 x 2.65 x 1 inches
    - Title: Film Splicer, undated (Folder 092.2.0265)
      Description: Film splicer for super 8 sound film, in original box
      Maker: Wurker--stamped on splicer, printed on box
      Where Made: "Made in Germany" stamped on bottom of splicer, printed on box
      Materials: Metal, plastic, cardboard
      Dimensions: 2.25 x 3.5 x 5.15 inches
    - Title: Focus enlarger, undated (Folder 092.2.0266)
      Description: Focus enlarger
      Maker: Label on bottom states "Bestwell optical Inst Co."
      Where Made: Label on bottom states "209 Beverly Road, Bklyn. 18, NY"
      Materials: Metal, glass, paint
      Dimensions: 6.35 x 2.5 x 6.5 inches
    - Title: Toy Spider, undated (Folder 092.2.0267)
      Description: Hand-made toy depicting spider, with string pull and roller underneath, black with green dots
      Materials: wood, leather, paint, string, rubber, rubber bands
      Dimensions: 1.15 x 4.5 x 3.65 inches
    - Title: Kachina, undated (Folder 092.2.0268)
      Description: Hand-carved wood Kachina doll featuring bull horns, protruding eyes, feathers on crown of head and tail. Multi-colored.
      Materials: wood, feathers, thread, paint
      Dimensions: 9 x 3.65 x 2 inches
    - Title: Kachina, undated (Folder 092.2.0269)
      Description: Hand-carved wood machine doll featuring feather headdress, bull horns, protruding eyes, leather skirt, with painted snake, beard, moccasins, and leopard fur cape. Multi-colored.
      Materials: wood, feathers, paper, paint, fur, leather, yarn
      Dimensions: 9 x 4.5 x 3.75 inches
    - Title: Kachina, undated (Folder 092.2.0270)
      Description: Hand-carved wood Kachina doll featuring geometric headdress with feathers, geometric designs, protruding mouth/nose. Multi-colored.Note: object not freestanding
      Materials: wood, feathers, paint
      Dimensions: 11 x 2.5 x 2.25 inches
    - Title: Kachina, undated (Folder 092.2.0271)
      Description: Hand-carved wood Kachina doll featuring protruding mouth, butterfly in back of head; black & white & terracotta.
      Maker: Label bottom of right foot reads "Nayaiataka"
      Materials: wood, paint, feather, string
      Dimensions: 5.25 x 3.15 x 2 inches
    - Title: Kachina, undated (Folder 092.2.0272)
      Description: Hand-carved wood Kachina doll featuring stick headdress, pronounced yoke or collar on neck, tail in back. Multi-colored.
      Dimensions: 7.5 x 2.25 x 2.25 inches
    - Title: Kachina/Squash-man figure, undated (Folder 092.2.0273)
      Description: Hand-carved wood Kachina doll with human male body and squash---shaped head; painted green and black stripes, yellow disc on back of head, yellow maracas in hands, cloth loincloth attached, glued to wood base.
      Maker: Bottom of base reads "Squash by Andrea Naha"
      Materials: wood, paint, cloth, leather, yarn, glue
      Dimensions: 8.5 x 4.25 x 4 inches
    - Title: Kachina/Figurine, undated (Folder 092.2.0274)
      Description: Kachina-esque figurine of male body with head covered by hood with geometric symbols, fur trim around neck, loincloth with geometric designs, yarn tied around ankles--sticks held in each hand. Back loincloth broken off.
      Maker: Markings on bottom of feet illegible
      Materials: clay, paint, fur, yarn, wood
      Dimensions: 6.75 x 5.25 x 2 inches
    - Title: Miniature Kachina, undated (Folder 092.2.0275)
      Description: Carved wood Kachina dancing figure with Mohawk, loincloth, tail, moccasins. Body painted half yellow, half green.
      Materials: wood, paint, fur glue
      Dimensions: 5.25 x 2.75 x 2.25 inches
    - Title: Figurine, undated (Folder 092.2.0276)
      Description: Figurine of mythological character or god, featuring plumed headdress, wings, and leopard spots; probably Latin-American
      Dimensions: 7 x 4.25 x 3.25 inches
    - Title: Figurine, undated (Folder 092.2.0277)
      Description: Hand-carved wood figure, unfinished, unpainted, featuring long hair and bangs.
      Dimensions: 6.25 x 3.75 x 2 inches
    - Title: Miniature figurine, undated (Folder 092.2.0278)
      Description: Miniature of Native American dancer wearing feathered headdress, mask, skirt and feather cuffs on arms. Multi-colored.
      Dimensions: 2.5 x 2.5 x 1 inches
    - Title: Miniature Mask, undated (Folder 092.2.0279)
      Description: Mask depicting jaguar face with open mouth and teeth and straw plumes projecting from face
      Maker: markings on back illegible
      Materials: wood, paint, straw
      Dimensions: 2.75 x 4.75 x 1.5 inches
    - Title: Wooden slats--engraved, undated (Folder 092.2.0280)
      Description: "Book" composed of narrow wooden leaves attached by string through center. Each leaf or slat is engraved with scenes depicting mythological figures & writing on back. Probably East Asian--shows Chinese influence
      Maker: none identifiable
      Materials: wood, paint, metal coin, string
      Dimensions: 9.75 x 1.5 x 0.75 inches
    - Title: Double-headed figurine, undated (Folder 092.2.0281)
      Description: Siamese-twin figurine featuring two heads on either end of torso, double faces on each head, black and white stripes on body and illegible inscription on both sides of torso. Both heads have glass tops revealing bark or hair inside.
      Materials: plaster, paint, glass, hair, wire, bark or bone, string
      Dimensions: 10 x 8.5 x 1.5 inches
    - Title: Paperweight-globe, undated (Folder 092.2.0282)
      Description: Multi-colored globe encase in clear Lucite cube
      Materials: Lucite, metal
      Dimensions: 2 x 2 x 2 inches
    - Title: Globe, undated (Folder 092.2.0283)
      Description: Hollow metal globe, multi-colored, probably meant to come apart as container. Items duplicate of 092.2.0284 and 092.2.0285
      Dimensions: 1.65 inches
    - Title: Globe, undated (Folder 092.2.0284)
      Description: Hollow metal globe, multi-colored, probably meant to come apart as a container; item is duplicate of 092.2.0283 and 092.2.0258
    - Title: Globe, undated (Folder 092.2.0285)
      Description: Hollow metal globe, multi-colored, opens up as a container. Item is duplicate of 092.2.0283 and 092.2.0284
    - Title: Globe, undated (Folder 092.2.0286)
      Description: Miniature globe opens up a into container. Multi-colored. Item is duplicate of 092.2.0287-092.2.0290
      Dimensions: 1 inches
    - Title: Globe, undated (Folder 092.2.0287)
      Description: Miniature globe opens up as container; multi-colored. Item is duplicate of 092.2.0286-092.2.0290
    - Title: Globe, undated (Folder 092.2.0288)
    - Title: Globe, undated (Folder 092.2.0290)
    - Title: Globe, undated (Folder 092.2.0291)
      Description: Globe on stand which depicts signs of the zodiac, the seasons and months of the year. Seam along circumference of globe forms a lip. Multi-colored
      Maker: "off the coast of Chile, printed ""Ohio Art Co., Bryan Ohio""n.d."
      Where Made: Ohio USA--printed on globe (near Chile)
      Dimensions: 8.75 x 6 x 6inches
    - Title: Globes, undated (Folder 092.2.0292)
      Description: Globe on stand with paint removed to reveal tin surface, with wooden figure (broken) and cardboard cylinder shell of firework attached with yellow wire
      Maker: none, but possible David Wojnarowicz